Without EUV,
will the semiconductor industry
be over?
This EUV machine costs 181 million USD.
Not only is it expensive,
it also occupies a pivotal position
in the chip industry chain.
Under the restrictions of
the U.S. CHIPS Act,
ASML is prohibited from
exporting EUV machines to China.
Even its EUV machines in Taiwan
have kill switches installed.
ASML has prepared for the worst,
making sure that
this technology cannot be stolen
even China invades Taiwan.
But why exactly is this machine
sought after by the whole world?
Can't we just build
another company like ASML?
The key technology of making chips
has been around since 1957.
It is essentially
stacking materials on silicon wafers.
Only that each layer of material
needs to be etched with patterns
through photolithography
before the next layer stacks on.
So does the next layer.
To ensure patterns on chips are correct,
in 1957,
Lathrop developed
the photolithography process.
Let's do a quick review of this.
First,
grow the desired material on a wafer.
Then coat it with photoresist.
The next step—exposure—is the key.
Place a photomask
between the UV light source and the wafer.
The mask is with a carved-out pattern.
The mask itself blocks UV light.
The UV light passing through the hollow part
will change the chemical properties
of the photoresist.
Take negative photoresist for example.
The photoresist exposed to UV light
becomes insoluble.
When rinsed with a solvent,
these parts remain.
The parts that were not exposed to the UV
due to the mask's blocking
will be rinsed away.
Finally, add hydrofluoric acid or other solvents.
The area on the wafer
not protected by photoresist
will be etched by the solvent
with desired patterns.
Now, congratulations,
one lithography process is completed.
You have printed
the first layer of a chip.
Next, just repeat the process
again and again.
Finally, you should build
3D chips on the wafer.
When we want to make smaller chips,
we should try to leave finer patterns
on the photoresist.
In the past,
simply shrinking the size of the mask
allows patterns to be smaller and smaller.
But when a mask
shrinks to a certain degree,
diffraction occurs.
To be precise,
when the slits of a mask are thinner
than half the light's wavelength,
the light diffracts.
When passing through such slits,
the light will not only go straight,
but also make a turn
at the edge of the slits,
casting the wrong pattern.
In other words,
although we can keep shrinking the mask,
but to ensure the accuracy of a pattern,
the size of each feature within
cannot be smaller than
half the wavelength of the light.
For example, in the early 2000s,
the light source used at that time
was laser.
Its wavelength had been reduced
from krypton fluoride's (KrF2)
248 nanometers
to argon fluoride's (ArF) 193 nanometers.
This 193-nanometer laser
is of course inadequate
to the task for current sub-7nm processes.
To get around this physical limit,
scientists tried various methods
such as immersion lithography
and multiple patterning.
Immersion lithography is to spread
a layer of water or other liquid
between the light source and the wafer
to improve the path of light.
This is a bit like,
when using a high-magnification microscope,
we would put a drop of immersion oil
between the lens and the sample.
Multiple patterning is to divide
a pattern into multiple exposures.
For example,
if there are 6 lines—1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,—
to be exposed,
the lines can be divided into two passes.
The first pass exposes line 1, 3, and 5.
The second 2, 4, and 6.
This act of
adding the spacing between lines
can reduce diffraction as much as possible.
These methods are collectively called
resolution enhancement techniques—RET.
They are meant to achieve higher resolution
at a given wavelength
by redesigning
lithography processes.
In addition, upon diffraction,
the UV light deviates more and more
as the distance between the mask
and the wafer increases.
In the 1970s,
some researchers
placed the mask right on the wafer,
making the mask touch the photoresist
to minimize the distance between the two.
But with this method,
when the mask was lifted after exposure,
it was usually glued with photoresist
and damaged the wafer.
Eventually, this approach was abandoned.
Researchers turned to
developing the mask aligner instead.
Using precision equipment,
they can finely adjust
the distance between the mask and the wafer
and other parameters
to reduce diffraction.
With these improvements,
although the light source at that time
was the deep ultraviolet laser—DUV—
with a 193-nanometer wavelength,
amazingly,
we still advanced all the way
to the 7nm process node.
This deserves a round of applause.
But below 7 nanometers,
DUV lithography ultimately met
its bottleneck.
Scientists still had to
resort to light with shorter wavelengths.
You might think that
what's so difficult about that?
It is incredibly difficult.
For example,
light must be focused through lenses,
but ordinary glass lenses
absorb short-wavelength UV light.
Ultraviolet light with wavelengths
below 185 nanometers
can even be absorbed by air.
Therefore, the entire lithography process
must be conducted in a vacuum.
If you dig into these issues,
you'll find more difficulties.
Anyway,
some researchers were finally determined
to develop a light
with less than one-tenth the wavelength,
the 13.5-nanometer
extreme ultraviolet light—EUV.
Thus began a great project
that would take 30 years,
cost billions of dollars,
and turned out to be achieved by
only one company in the world.
In previous episodes, we mentioned that
the leader of the photolithography
equipment market kept changing.
Since Lathrop invented this technology,
From Texas Instruments, PerkinElmer, GCA,
to Nikon and Canon in the 1980s...
Successively, they have been
the key manufacturers at different times.
Eventually, in the 1990s, a crucial period,
a new challenger, ASML, emerged.
Nikon, Canon, and ASML
became the three giants competing
in the lithography equipment market.
However, a decision made by Intel
altered the competitive landscape.
At that time, the lab led by Intel
and the US government believed that
Japan's semiconductor industry
was developing rapidly
and that many businesses
once belonging to the U.S.
were snatched away by Japan.
If they wanted to invest in
an equipment manufacturer,
they should choose the Dutch one,
which was more neutral.
Therefore,
Intel decided to partner with ASML,
starting a 30-year-long R&D collaboration.
Although this project required
a huge amount of time, money, and energy,
the massive investment
would put ASML in an unshakable position
as a leader in photolithography
30 years later.
Intel hoped ASML could develop
an EUV equipment
featuring 13.5 nanometer light
to address smaller process nodes
in the future.
But just figuring out how to generate
a steady 13.5 nm light source
was an enormous challenge
because not a laser source or light bulb
can directly emit 13.5-nanometer light.
To emit EUV,
there must be high-energy plasma.
The way to produce it is using high-intensity lasers
to hit the target,
making the target instantly generate the plasma
that emits EUV.
For the mission of
producing EUV with plasma,
ASML chose another laser-making company,
Cymer, to do the job.
Cymer's task was not simple at all.
They had to design a process
that uses carbon dioxide lasers
to bombard tin metal to generate EUV.
All in all,
this process
is certainly much more difficult
than just lighting a bulb.
First, the tin metal must be turned into
Sn droplet of 30 micrometers in diameter.
and be shot out by an emitter
at a speed of 300 kilometers per hour
through a vacuum chamber.
There's more.
Each Sn droplet will be hit
by a high-power carbon dioxide laser twice.
The first hit is for
heating the Sn droplet
and making it expand.
The second one
heats it up to 220,000 degrees Celsius,
turning it into a scorching plasma
whose temperature is fourty times
then that of the sun’s surface.
As such, this high-temperature plasma
will radiate short-wavelength ultraviolet light,
which is EUV.
However, this is just a short EUV pulse.
To generate a steady streak of EUV,
this process needs to be repeated
50,000 times per second.
In building this bombardment equipment,
what was just described
was just about 1% of the difficulty.
For example,
just to create this laser,
Cymer went to another laser-making company
—TRUMPF.
TRUMPF took 10 years to build this laser.
Eventually, the laser emitter
consists of
more than 450,000 parts.
Why make it so complicated?
It turns out that
after the laser hits the Sn droplet
the tin will be blasted into debris
which affects EUV generation.
Therefore,
the Sn droplet must move fast
and the laser must be precisely controlled
for perfect timing
so that the Sn droplet
can keep entering the reaction chamber
to generate steady EUV light.
As an aside,
in addition to tin,
they have also considered other elements—
for example, xenon plasma that can emit
a shorter EUV wavelength
of only 11 nanometers.
But the EUV intensity emitted by xenon
was insufficient.
Tin was still the best choice.
Up to this point,
only half the problems are solved.
The other half lies in
the lithography process.
The light
still needs to pass through
a series of lens sets
to be cast on chips.
The biggest challenge here is that
EUV is easily absorbed by substances.
To avoid the EUV reacting with air,
the chamber is pumped into a vacuum.
This is probably the simplest step of all.
The real challenge is that
even lenses themselves absorb EUV.
This top-level challenge
should be dealt with by a top-notch company.
The leading company in optics from Germany,
Zeiss, undertook this task.
First,
they had to rule out using lens' refraction
as a way to focus the light
because as long as EUV
passes through lenses,
it will be greatly attenuated
by absorption.
Therefore, optical columns in EUV machines
are an all-reflective system
which is entirely composed of mirrors.
Although being reflective,
mirrors can still absorb EUV.
Eventually, Zeiss coated the mirrors
with two types of layers
—silicon and molybdenum—
overlapping each other
dozens to a hundred times,
forming a device called
the Bragg mirror.
When light goes through these layers
with alternating refractive indices,
the Bragg mirror can raise its reflectivity
by creating more reflection
and constructive interference.
Now this may sound feasible,
but it is still
a very very very difficult task.
This episode is sponsored by
Micro-Epsilon Taiwan.
Thanks to them, we are able to realize
the pinnacle of human technology.
To accurately cast the EVU at the target,
these mirrors must be incredibly smooth.
How smooth?
If the mirrors were scaled up to
let’s say the size of the entire Taiwan island,
the height deviation on the mirrors
can only be less than 0.01 millimeter.
That's about the width of a hair.
The optical precision of this system
is like standing on Earth
and trying to aim a laser pointer
at a ping pong ball on the Moon.
Only through this,
the hard-earned EUV light
can be reflected and focused multiple times
to pass right through
the nanometer-scale photomask
and land on the photoresist.
Intel's Director of Lithography,
Mark Phillips, once said
EUV is the most precise instrument
ever made by humans.
It is the ultimate manifestation
of human technology.
For real-time control and correction
of these mirror sets, masks,
and the movement of the wafer stages
ultra-high precision sensors are required.
Devices such as capacitive sensors,
eddy current inductive sensors,
or optical ones
such as confocal chromatic sensors
and white light interferometer
—sensors of different measurement mechanisms—
can cater to different circumstances
and materials,
achieving sub-nanometer precision.
They are the core measurement tools
in many precision industries
such as the semiconductor industry.
The manufacture of
many sensors in EUV machines
is entrusted to Micro-Epsilon
for customized development.
In addition to
the well-known chromatic confocal technology,
there are other optical
and non-optical methods
to monitor such a high-tech beast
like the EUV machine.
For example,
if a mirror set moves slightly,
the capacitive sensors
will sense the displacement
through changes in the dielectric.
In fact,
there are nearly
a thousand sensors from Micro-Epsilon
in an EUV machine.
Inside it,
not only the mirror set need correction
but also the photomask.
If its position is slightly off,
defects will occur
when the pattern is being down-sized
and printed on wafers.
This will subsequently affect yield.
After all,
current semiconductors are so small
that even a few layers of atoms
will make a big difference.
In addition,
the position of the wafer
in relation to the mask also matters.
Since we can't move
the laser and optical parts
that have been painstakingly aligned,
the wafer becomes the one part
that can be moved during exposure.
The dual-stage system of the EUV machine
can move two wafers simultaneously.
One undergoes exposure
while the other is measured for precision
at the same time.
The stages move at high speed
with six degrees of freedom.
The sensors used here
are eddy current sensors
with nanometer-level precision.
Because Micro-Epsilon Group
values the Taiwan market,
in 2022,
it established a subsidiary in Taiwan
—Micro-Epsilon Taiwan—
to provide more localized service
for manufacturers in Taiwan.
From standard catalog items
to customized products
matching clients' needs,
it provides Taiwan customers with
sensor solutions of ultra-high precision.
Through experience in collaborating
with top manufacturers
such as ASML and Zeiss,
it can offer assistance in upgrading
Taiwan's semiconductor equipment.
In measuring displacement
and positioning components
of equipment in every supply chain,
Micro-Epsilon sensors
can be seen everywhere
such as in Lapping machine
temporary bonding equipment,
Dispensing machine,
high-precision die bonders,
wafer metrology machine and so on.
As of now,
I believe everyone understands that,
in the rise of the semiconductor industry,
why chip design, chip manufacturing,
and equipment manufacturing
are so closely related and highly symbiotic.
Let's go back to the birth of
the EUV machine.
History tells us
Zeiss and Cymer
both fulfilled their missions.
ASML has been dominating the market
ever since it built the first prototype of
an EUV machine in 2006.
Can there be another company
matching ASML?
Probably not.
A company of this scale
with countless innovations
and integrations of technology
requires decades of development
and a billion-dollar investment to build.
On the flip side,
should we worry about
ASML monopolizing the market?
Well, its monopoly is already a fact,
but ASML is not alone.
As you can see
in the previous introduction,
the birth of EUV machines
was based on the joint efforts of
many companies and suppliers,
especially the U.S. company Cymer,
who built the tin droplet
bombardment equipment
and the German company Zeiss,
who made the reflective mirrors.
Only 15% of the components
are produced by ASML itself.
Its key technology lies in
assembling these parts
into a working EUV machine.
Although ASML later acquired Cymer
and invested in Zeiss,
the EUV machine cannot be developed by
a single company or country alone.
It represents cutting-edge technology
created through collaboration
among many countries and companies.
Right now,
ASML has already aimed at
sub-2nm processes.
Last year, it launched the latest
high numerical aperture EUV machine
and sold the first one to Intel.
Rumor has it that TSMC has already acquired an EUV machine.
But it's still considered classified information.
We'll just have to wait and see on this one.
This is the end of this episode.
Next time when you see an ASML truck,
remember to drive carefully.
You don't want to pay for a car accident like this.
See you next time.